let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1.,
        question: 'The best use of linear programming is to find optimal use of',
        answer: 'D. All of the above',
        options: [
            'A. Money',
            'B. Manpower',
            'C. Machine',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    },

    {
        numb: 2.,
        question: 'While plotting constraints on a graph paper, terminal points on both the axes are connected by a straight line because',
        answer: 'D. All of the above',
        options: [
            'A. The resources are limited in supply',
            'B. The objective function as a linear function',
            'C. The constraints are linear equations or inequalities',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3.,
        question: 'Which of the following is not a characteristics of the LP model',
        answer: 'B. An objective function of maximization type',
        options: [
            'A. Alternative courses of action',
            'B. An objective function of maximization type',
            'C. Limited amount of resources',
            'D. Non-negativity condition on the value of decision variables'
        ]
    },

    {
        numb: 4.,
        question: 'If the number of available constraints is 3 and the number of parameters to be optimized is 4 then',
        answer: 'B. The constraints are short in number',
        options: [
            'A. The objective function can be optimized',
            'B. The constraints are short in number',
            'C. The solution is problem oriented',
            'D. None of these'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5.,
        question: 'Maximization of objective function in an LP model means',
        answer: 'A. Value occurs at allowable set of decisions',
        options: [
            'A. Value occurs at allowable set of decisions',
            'B. Highest value is chosen among allowable decisions',
            'C. None of the above',
            'D. Both (A) & (B)'
        ]
    },

    {
        numb: 6.,
        question: 'The graphical method of LP uses',
        answer: 'D. All of the above',
        options: [
            'A. Objective function equation',
            'B. Constraint equations',
            'C. Linear equations',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7.,
        question: 'Which of the following is an assumption of an LP model',
        answer: 'D. All of the above',
        options: [
            'A. Divisibility',
            'B. Proportionality',
            'C. Additivity',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    },

    {
        numb: 8.,
        question: 'Which of the following is not a characteristics of the LP',
        answer: 'D. The problem must be of minimization type',
        options: [
            'A. Resources must be limited',
            'B. only one objective function',
            'C. Parameters value remains constant during planning period',
            'D. The problem must be of minimization type'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9.,
        question: 'The best use of linear programming technique is find an optimal use of',
        answer: 'D. All of the above',
        options: [
            'A. Money',
            'B. Manpower',
            'C. Machine',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    },

    {
        numb: 10.,
        question: 'The distinguishing feature of an LP model is',
        answer: 'A. Relationship among all variables is linear',
        options: [
            'A. Relationship among all variables is linear',
            'B. It has a single objective function & constraints',
            'C. Value of decision variables is non-negative',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11.,
        question: 'Linear programming is a',
        answer: 'D. All of the above',
        options: [
            'A. Constrained optimization technique',
            'B. Technique for economic allocation of limited resources',
            'C. Mathematical technique',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    },

    {
        numb: 12.,
        question: 'In LPP______',
        answer: 'C. Both (A) & (B)',
        options: [
            'A. objective function is linear',
            'B. constraints are linear',
            'C. Both (A) & (B)',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },

    {
        numb: 13.,
        question: 'A solution which optimizes the objective function called as _____',
        answer: 'D. Optimal solution',
        options: [
            'A. Solution',
            'B. Basic solution',
            'C. Feasible solution',
            'D. Optimal solution'
        ]
    },


    {
        numb: 14.,
        question: 'A solution which satisfies non-negative conditions also is called as',
        answer: 'C. Feasible solution',
        options: [
            'A. Solution',
            'B. Basic solution',
            'C. Feasible solution',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },

    {
        numb: 15.,
        question: 'The graph x<=2 and y>=2 will be situated at the',
        answer: 'A. First and second quadrant',
        options: [
            'A. First and second quadrant',
            'B. second and third quadrant',
            'C. first and third quadrant',
            'D. third and fourth quadrant'
        ]
    },

    {
        numb: 16.,
        question: 'A basic solution is called non-degenerate , if',
        answer: 'B. None of the basic variables is zero',
        options: [
            'A. All the basic variables are zero',
            'B. None of the basic variables is zero',
            'C. At least one of the basic variables is zero',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },

    {
        numb: 17.,
        question: 'The intermediates solutions of constraints must be checked by substituting them back into',
        answer: 'B. cConstraint equations',
        options: [
            'A. Objective function',
            'B. Constraint equations',
            'C. Not required',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },

    {
        numb: 18.,
        question: 'Maximization of objective function in LPP means',
        answer: 'A. Value occurs at allowable set decision',
        options: [
            'A. Value occurs at allowable set decision',
            'B. Highest value is chosen among allowable decision',
            'C. None of the above',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    },

    {
        numb: 19.,
        question: 'The linear function of the variables which is to be maximize is called',
        answer: 'B. Objective function',
        options: [
            'A. Constraints',
            'B. Objective function',
            'C. Decision variable',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },

    {
        numb: 20.,
        question: 'Operation research approach is',
        answer: 'D. All of the above',
        options: [
            'A. Multi-disciplinary',
            'B. Artificial',
            'C. Intuitive',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    }
]
